<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Ninjamatic!</string>
    <string name="main_menu">Main Menu</string>
    <string name="block_created">% created</string>
    <string name="icon_inv">INV</string>
    <string name="icon_map">MAP</string>
    <string name="icon_menu">MENU</string>
    <string name="icon_id">ID</string>
    <string name="click_on_a_block">Click on a block to identify</string>
    <string name="that_is">That is %</string>
    <string name="loading_map">Please wait - loading map&#8230;</string>
    <string name="finished_saving_game">Please wait - loading map&#8230;</string>
    <string name="out_of_time">You have run out of time!</string>
    <string name="amulet_distance">Distance</string>
    <string name="time_remaining">Time Left</string>
    <string name="need_rocks">You must collect more rocks!</string>
    <string name="area_not_empty">Area not empty</string>
    <string name="none_left">You have none left</string>
    <string name="no_item_selected">You must select a block first</string>
    <string name="replay_map">Replay Map</string>
    <string name="return_text">Return</string>
    <string name="game_over">GAME OVER</string>
    <string name="abandon">Abandon</string>
    <string name="eat">Eat</string>
    <string name="inventory">Inventory</string>
    <string name="select_block">Select a Block or Item to Use</string>
    <string name="no_items">You have no items</string>
    <string name="select_item_to_eat">Select an item to eat</string>
    <string name="cant_eat">You can\'t eat that!</string>
    
    <string name="nothing">Nothing</string>
    <string name="grass">Grass</string>
    <string name="soil">Soil</string>
    <string name="rock">Rock</string>
    <string name="water">Water</string>
    <string name="fire">Fire</string>
    <string name="ladder">Ladder</string>
    <string name="wood">Wood</string>
    <string name="dynamite">Dynamite</string>
    <string name="tangleweed">Tangleweed</string>
    <string name="apple">Apple</string>
    <string name="chest">Chest</string>
    <string name="coal">Coal</string>
    <string name="gold">Gold</string>
    <string name="lava">Lava</string>
    <string name="monster_gen">Monster Gen</string>
    <string name="snow">Snow</string>
    <string name="tree">Tree</string>
    <string name="acorn">Acorn</string>
    <string name="tree_branch">Tree Branch</string>
    <string name="flint">Flint</string>
    <string name="adamantium">Adamantium</string>
    <string name="iron_ore">Iron Ore</string>
    <string name="sand">Sand</string>
    <string name="wheat">Wheat</string>
    <string name="amulet">Amulet</string>
    <string name="slime">Slime</string>
    <string name="stone">Stone</string>
    <string name="wheat_seed">Wheat Seed</string>
    <string name="metal_girder">Metal Girder</string>
    <string name="tree_roots">Tree Roots</string>
    <string name="wheat_roots">Wheat Roots</string>
    <string name="wool">Wool</string>
    <string name="weeds">Weeds</string>
    <string name="sticks">Sticks</string>
    <string name="crafting_table">Crafting Table</string>
    <string name="bones">Bones</string>
    <string name="cobweb">Cobweb</string>
    <string name="lamb_chop">Lamp Chop</string>
    <string name="unlit_furnace">Unlit Furnace</string>
    <string name="lit_furnace">Lit Furnace</string>
    <string name="bread">Bread</string>
    <string name="glass">Glass</string>
    <string name="clay">Clay</string>
    <string name="bricks">Bricks</string>
    <string name="bed">Bed</string>
    <string name="raw_beef">Raw Beef</string>
    <string name="raw_chicken">Raw Chicken</string>
    <string name="raw_pork">Raw Pork</string>
    <string name="pork">Pork</string>
    <string name="egg">Egg</string>
    <string name="player">Player</string>
    <string name="alien">Alien</string>
    <string name="chicken">Chicken</string>
    <string name="cow">Cow</string>
    <string name="sheep">Sheep</string>
    <string name="pig">Pig</string>
    <string name="wasp">Wasp</string>
    <string name="zombie">Zombie</string>
    <string name="skeleton">Skeleton</string>
    <string name="space_invader">Space Invader</string>
    <string name="block_types">Block Types</string>
    <string name="text_not_found">Text Not Found</string>
    <string name="desc_acorn">The acorn can be planted by throwing it onto soil, where it will grow into a tree if surrounded to the left, right and bottom by soil (not grass!) and be in sunlight.</string>
    <string name="desc_tangleweed">If given enough space and agitated, tangleweed can grow out of control!</string>
    <string name="desc_soil">Soil is required to grow trees and wheat.</string>
    <string name="desc_rock">Rocks are the players main means of defence other than hiding.  After being collected, rocks can be thrown by the player at attacking monsters.</string>
    <string name="desc_water">Water will expand to fill up its area.  A player will be harmed if they are underwater for too long, although they can hold their breath initially.</string>
    <string name="desc_dynamite">If damaged, it will explode, harming things that are close by and creating a hole.</string>
    <string name="desc_apple">An apple will increase the player\'s health by 10 up to the maximum.</string>
    <string name="desc_chest">A chest can be opened to reveal a random item of treasure.</string>
    <string name="desc_monster_gen">Usually found in dungeons, these will create random monsters at predetermined intervals.</string>
    <string name="desc_adamantium">This cannot be destroyed in any way.</string>
    <string name="desc_flint">If you throw flint at a block of iron ore, it will start a fire.</string>
    <string name="desc_iron_ore">Iron ore can be used to make fire with Flint.</string>
    <string name="desc_fire">Fire can be created using flint and iron ore.  A fire will spread to adjacent flammable blocks, and will harm the player if they touch it.  A fire is also required to light a furnace.</string>
    <string name="desc_lava">Lava will expand to fill up its area.  A player will be harmed if they touch lava.  If lava encounters water, it will turn into rock.</string>
    <string name="desc_amulet">Obtaining amulets is the objective of Adventure Mode and Race Mode.</string>
    <string name="desc_slime">Bubbling slime will harm the player.  Also, beware of blobs of slime that might spurt out!</string>
    <string name="desc_gold">Gold does not currently serve any purpose other than to make the player feel better about themselves.</string>
    <string name="desc_stone">Stone usually lines the walls of a dungeon, and is a bit harder to mine than rock.</string>
    <string name="desc_sand">Sand is usually found at the bottom of water.</string>
    <string name="desc_wheat">Wheat can be grown from a wheat seed.  Wheat has 3 levels of growth - short, medium and long.  If left for too long, wheat can go to seed.</string>
    <string name="desc_wheat_root">Wheat roots are created when wheat seeds are thrown onto soil, where it will grow into wheat.</string>
    <string name="desc_wheat_seed">The wheat seed will grow into wheat if it thrown onto soil.  It must be surrounded to the left, right and bottom by soil (not grass!) and be in sunlight.</string>
    <string name="desc_tree_root">Tree roots are created when an acorn is thrown onto soil, where it will grow into a tree.</string>
    <string name="desc_bed">A bed can be made by crafting wool and sticks together.  If a bed is built, then the player will spawn on it when loading a previously saved map.  If the player builds multiple beds, a random bed will be chosen as the starting point.</string>
    <string name="desc_wool">Wool is obtained by killing a sheep and can be used to make a bed.</string>
    <string name="desc_wood">Wood is created by crafting two blocks of tree trunk together.</string>
    <string name="desc_lit_furnace">A furnace can be created by crafting two blocks of stone.  It can be lit by placing a fire next to it, although it may go out again after some time.  A furnace can be used to craft items by placing certain kinds of block on top of them.</string>
    <string name="desc_bread">Bread is made by placing wheat on top of a furnace.  The bread can then be consumed to give the player extra health.</string>
    <string name="desc_crafting_table">A crafting table can be made by crafting wood and sticks.  A crafting table is required to craft more advanced items.</string>
    <string name="desc_sticks">Sticks are created by crafting two blocks of wood.</string>
    <string name="desc_clay">Clay can be found in the ground, and can be used on a furnace to create bricks.</string>
    <string name="desc_bricks">Bricks are made using clay, and are considerably stronger than other materials and will provide good protection against monsters.</string>
    <string name="game_modes">Game Modes</string>
    <string name="construction">Construction</string>
    <string name="survival">Survival</string>
    <string name="farming">Farming</string>
    <string name="quest">Quest</string>
    <string name="race">Race</string>
    <string name="desc_construction">In Construction mode, there are no enemies and the player starts of with an infinite supply of all the major raw blocks.  This allows the player the freedom to construct anything they want.</string>
    <string name="desc_survival">The objective of Survival Mode is to survive as long as possible.  In Survival Mode, there are monsters which will attack the player, and only monsters that the player\'s avatar can see are shown.  In addition, the player\'s health is slowly reduced, so the player must grow or find food to survive.</string>
    <string name="desc_farming">In Farming mode, there are no monsters.  The player starts off with no resources, and must gather seeds with which to grow their own food to survive, as the player\'s health is slowly reduced over time.</string>
    <string name="desc_quest">The objective of Adventure Mode is to find as many Amulets as possible.  The player is only told the distance to the next amulet, but not the direction.  Only monsters that the player\'s avatar can see are shown.  Enemies might be just behind a block, and will only be revealed if the block is removed.</string>
    <string name="desc_race">In Race mode, you have a limited amount of time to get to the amulet.  However, there are no monsters in your way.\n\nOnce you have collected the amulet, another one is created.  How many can you collect?</string>
    <string name="gameplay">Gameplay</string>
    <string name="throwing">Throwing</string>
    <string name="health_bar">Health Bar</string>
    <string name="saving">Saving</string>
    <string name="desc_throwing">Throwing is for either attacking an enemy or crafting.  The currently selected block will be what is thrown, although only certain types of block can be thrown.  If the player is holding a type that cannot be thrown, a rock will be thrown instead.  A thrown item will be removed from the player\'s inventory; however, the item thrown will be returned to the player\'s inventory if no action is performed (e.g. the player misses the shot).</string>
    <string name="desc_health_bar">The health bar shows how much health the player has.  If it is reduced to zero, the game is over.</string>
    <string name="desc_saving">Saving the game will save the map and the player\'s current inventory.  It will be saved onto your SD Card into the % directory with the filename entered by the player, and these files can be shared with other players.\n\nWhen the game is re-loaded, the player\'s avater will return back to the starting location unless they have built a bed, in which case the player will start there.</string>
    <string name="desc_crafting">Crafting is using two or more blocks to create another new kind of block.  Crafting is always carried out by throwing one block at another block; for more complex recipes, one block needs to be placed on top of a table or a lit furnace.  For example, throwing an acorn block at soil will plant the seed, creating a root block that can grow into a tree.  Note that the area above the block must be empty.  There is a Crafting Guide which will show what \'recipes\' are available.</string>
    <string name="desc_zombies">Zombies roam the landscape at night, and can be generated by a Monster Generator at any time.  They will try and reach the player at which point they will zap their life energy.</string>
    <string name="desc_skeletons">Skeletons roam the landscape at night, and can be generated by a Monster Generator at any time.  They will try and reach the player at which point they will zap their life energy.  They will also thrown bones at the player.</string>
    <string name="desc_wasps">Killer Wasps can be generated by a Monster Generator at any time.  They will try and reach the player at which point they will zap their life energy.</string>
    <string name="mobs">Mobs</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="new_map">Start New Map</string>
    <string name="load_map">Load Saved Map</string>
    <string name="start_game">Start Game</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="more_games">More Games</string>
    <string name="no_thanks">No thanks</string>
    <string name="remind_later">"Remind me later"</string>
    <string name="kbd_enter">Enter</string>
    <string name="kbd_del">Del</string>
    <string name="version">Version</string>
    <string name="please_wait">Please Wait</string>

</resources>